## **Becky Todd**

Senior Developer Experience Writer at Atlassian

## Summary

I am passionate about developing content that enhances the developer experience. I have seven years' experience designing and authoring software documentation, including four years' experience supporting Agile software teams practicing Scrum and Kanban.

Specialties: Content Strategy, Information Architecture, Content Development, Technical Communication, Editing, Information Design, Style Guides

Software and technical skills include HTML, CSS, YAML, RESTful API Modeling Language (RAML), RESTful API documentation, Markdown, Git, Confluence, JIRA, Bitbucket, MadCap Flare, Adobe Creative Suite (Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign), Camtasia

## Experience

#### Senior Developer Experience Writer at Atlassian

November 2015 - Present

#### Founder and Organizer

June 2014 - January 2017 (2 years 7 months)

InfoDevDC is a Meetup group for information developers, technical writers, and other technical communication professionals.

We are on a mission to grow the technical communication community and encourage the free exchange of information. We also encourage first time speakers to get themselves out there and share their knowledge with others.

As the founder and main organizer, I am responsible for the following things:

- Scheduling events, including sourcing speakers and locations
- Coordinating joint events with other local technical communication groups
- Promoting events using social media and the Meetup site
- Assisting co-organizers with scheduling and managing events

#### **Senior Information Developer at Appian Corporation**

August 2014 - November 2015 (1 year 3 months)

• Acted as the InfoDev Chapter Lead in Engineering's tribal structure (Spotify model)

- Designed the content strategy, information architecture, and look and feel of documentation
- Managed content development for quarterly releases
- Served as technical editor for content written by subject matter experts
- Authored content using Markdown and used a static site generator to build content
- Acted as a product owner for technical documentation checked in to the core product Git repository
- Wrote and maintained the Appian Content Style Guide and Markdown Style Guide for Appian Content
- Managed another Information Developer

#### Senior Technical Writer at Netuitive

September 2011 - July 2014 (2 years 10 months)

- Managed requirements analysis, documentation deliverable life cycle, and content strategy for enterprise documentation deliverables
- Supported brand image by designing the look, feel, and voice of documentation
- Authored, edited, and maintained new and legacy documentation for Netuitive's core product, supporting products, and over 20 integrations
- Defined and oversaw departmental procedures, processes, and projects
- Mentored and trained a junior technical writer
- Collaborated with product management, quality assurance, support, and marketing
- Scripted and produced informational and tutorial videos

Senior Technical Writer, January 2014 – July 2014

Documentation Specialist II, January 2013 – January 2014

Documentation Specialist & Training Curriculum Developer, September 2011 – January 2013

#### Technical Writer at DataLink, Inc.

May 2010 - September 2011 (1 year 4 months)

- Authored and indexed software manuals and help systems for three products
- Managed over 100 pages of content
- Created the first quick reference booklets, which reduced support calls
- Designed marketing materials for professional printing
- Defined standards for the look, feel, and voice of documentation and marketing materials

#### Geek Squad Counter Intelligence Agent at Best Buy

August 2008 - August 2010 (2 years)

#### **Research Assistant**

2007 - 2008 (1 year)

- Conducted a research project concerning product efficiency of company paper sizes with minimal supervision
- Communicated with researchers and labs in other states and countries
- Gained experience with chemical safety in an industrial setting

- Assisted with technical work requests (TWRs) in order to complete day-to-day testing and research
- Experienced with GC, NMR, Mass Spec, HPGC, IR, other spectra, and paper-industry specific tests
- Responsible for running GC, IR, and other spectra as needed for TWRs
- Hazardous Materials and Lab Safety Certified, August 2006

#### Student Teaching Assistant & Scientific Stores at University of West Florida

August 2006 - December 2007 (1 year 4 months)

#### Education

#### University of California, Santa Cruz

2013 - 2013

#### **Missouri State University**

B.S., Professional Writing, 2009 - 2010

Activities and Societies: Society of Technical Communication (STC)

University of West Florida

Chemistry, 2006 - 2008

Activities and Societies: American Chemical Society Student Chapter

**Ozarks Technical Community College** 

A.A., General studies, 2000 - 2004

Activities and Societies: Phi Theta Kappa Honors Society, founding member of SAGE

**SHS** 2000

#### Honors and Awards

Appian Nexus Award, Exceptional Performance at Netuitiveuser documentation, graphics software, creating user-friendly technical documentation, new technology, digital photography

# **Becky Todd**

Senior Developer Experience Writer at Atlassian



Contact Becky on LinkedIn